Guide to the Papers of Rev. Richards A. Zariņš, 1883-2008 M1938
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 11. Printed material
  - Booklets
    - Irbe, Kārlis. Waj kultura bez reliģijas muhs izglahbs? Rīga, 1922 (Box 85, Folder 3)
    - Latwijas Behglu re-ewakuazijas beedribas darbibas pahrskats. 1920-1922. Rīga, 1922 (Box 85, Folder 3)
    - Veselis, Jānis. Leesma uz ūdeņeem: noveles. Rīga, 1922 (Box 85, Folder 3)
    - Kreicbergs, Jānis. Atmiņas par Krišjāni Valdemāru. Rīga, 1925 (Box 85, Folder 3)
    - Alfred Kalniņš: composer and organ-virtuoso-improviser. Criticisms. Rīga, 1927 (Box 85, Folder 3)
    - Lettonie. Plage et station balnaire de la Mer Baltique. Ville de Libau. Libau, 1927 (Box 85, Folder 3)
    - Wihtols, A. Ceswaines draudze: wehsturisks apskats. Ceswaine, 1929 (Box 85, Folder 3)
    - Swehtdeenas Rihts: weltits Smiltenes draudzes mahzitajam prahwestam Dr.Theol. H.C. K. Kundziņam wiņa 50 gadu amata swehtkos, 1930. gada 3. Maijā (Box 85, Folder 4)
    - Brāļu Kapi attēlos. Rīga, 1931 (Box 85, Folder 4)
    - Latvia: a tourist guide. Rīga, 1934 (Box 85, Folder 4)
    - Leepupes baznicas 150 gadi. Limbaži, 1934 (Box 85, Folder 4)
    - Visiem Ķīnā, Japānā un citās zemēs dzīvojošiem latvjiem. Rīga, 1934 (Box 85, Folder 4)
    - Dzimtenes atskaņas: Tēvijai, Latviešiem un Latvietībai veltītas. Tientzina, N. China, 1939 (Box 85, Folder 4)
    - Upīts, Andrejs. Varoņa pārnākšana. Maskava, 1942 (Box 85, Folder 4)
    - Bilmanis, Alfred. What Latvia wishes from this war: background, actual situation, hopes for future. Washington, D.C., 1943, 1944 (Box 85, Folder 4)
    - Erss, Adolfs. Stāsti: Telefons, Nevaļa, Dzīvā manta, Atriebība. Karavīra biblioteka. Rīga, 1944 (Box 85, Folder 5)
    - Grebzde, Irma. Pūra zirgs. Karavīra biblioteka. Rīga, 1944 (Box 85, Folder 5)
    - Krasts, Ilmārs. Gājiens pāri upei. Karavīra biblioteka. Rīga, 1944 (Box 85, Folder 5)
    - Jānīts nāca par gadskārtu. Rīga, 1944 (Box 85, Folder 5)
    - Truce, Austra. Mahzitaja Karla Podiņa dzihwes gahjums, 1872-1944. Ņujorkā, 1944 (Box 85, Folder 5)
    - The Baltic States: reprinted from The New Leader (New York) of 14th April, 1945. Edinburgh, 1945 (Box 85, Folder 5)
    - Bilmanis, Alfreds. The Church in Latvia. New York, 1945 (Box 85, Folder 5)
    - Bilmanis, Alfreds. The Church in Latvia. Washington D.C., 1945 (Box 85, Folder 5)
      2 booklets by alfreds Bilmanis, both published in 1945, differs in content and pagination
    - Akafist Presviatiei Vladychitsie nashei Bogoroditsie vsiekh skorbiashchikh radosti: po blagosloveniiu Preosviashchennago Ioanna, Episkopa Rizhskago. Gersbruk (Hersbruck, Bavaria), 1946 (Box 85, Folder 6)
    - Apsīšu Jēkabs. Bagāti radi. Fišbacha (Fischbach), 1946 (Box 85, Folder 6)
    - Dziesmu vaiņags. Fišbacha pie Nirnbergas (Fischbach bei Nürnberg), 1946 (Box 85, Folder 6)
    - Dziļleja, K. Cilvēks trimdā = Man in exile. Esslingen, Baden-Württemberg, 1946 (Box 85, Folder 6)
    - Dziļums, Alfreds. Pelni: noveles. Bornsene (Börnsen, Schleswig-Holstein), 1946 (Box 85, Folder 6)
    - Hunter-Blair, John. Valdis un Velta in England. Halle Westfalen (North-Rhine, Westphalia), Latvian camp, 1946 (Box 85, Folder 6)
    - Jāņa Evanģēlijs. Augsburg, Bavaria, 1946 (Box 85, Folder 6)
    - Kuršinskis, Imants. Rīgas miniatūras. Augsburga, 1946 (Box 85, Folder 6)
    - Latviešu tautas pasakas: Niklava Strunkes grafiskais ietērps. Geesthacht, Schleswig-Holstein, 1946 (Box 86, Folder 1)
    - Razna, Stanislavs. Himna brīvībai. Buchloe, Bavaria, 1946 (Box 86, Folder 1)
    - Riekste, Anna. Mierinājums: dzejoļi: veltījums mātei tālumā. Halle Westfalen, North Rine-Westpalia, 1946 (Box 86, Folder 1)
    - Skalbe, Kārlis. Pīlītes. [Place of publication not identified], 1946 (Box 86, Folder 1)
    - Skalbe, Kārlis. Zelta lāpa: pēdējo darbu izlase Jāņa Rudzīša sakārtojumā. Bornsene (Börnsen, Schleswig-Holstein), 1946 (Box 86, Folder 1)
    - Tēvu Jāņu dziesmas [Jānīts nāca par gadskārtu]. Trimdā, 1946. g. jūnijā (Box 86, Folder 1)
    - Appeal of the representatives of the Baltic nations to the General Assembly of the United Nations. Jointly presented on November 24, 1947, by the envoys of the three Baltic states, Lithuania, Latvia and Estonia. [Place of publication not identified], 1947 (Box 86, Folder 2)
    - Kalniņš, Kārlis. Do you know that Latvia--?: facts on the achievements of Latvia during the period 1918-1939. Eslingen, Baden-Württemberg, 1947 (Box 86, Folder 2)
    - Doku Atis. Laimīgā vasara u. c. stāsti un pasakas. Eslingen, Baden-Württemberg, 1947 (Box 86, Folder 2)
    - Dziļleja, K. Mans brālītis: bērnības dienu tēlojumi. Gunzburg, Bavaria, 1947 (Box 86, Folder 2)
    - Ernests Mauriņš: Lettischer kunstler graphiker und maler. Emmendingen, Baden-Württemberg, 1947 (Box 86, Folder 2)
      2 copies: in German and French
    - Liepiņš, Oļģerts. Piemineklis: stāsts. Trimdā, 1947 (Box 86, Folder 2)
    - Skujiņa, Rūta. Mani bērnības draugi. Altgarge (Alt Garge, Lower Saxony), 1947 (Box 86, Folder 2)
    - Šalme, Fr. Angliski-vāciski-latviska techniska vārdnīca. Esslingen am Neckar, Baden-Württemberg 1947 (Box 86, Folder 3)
    - Šlabrendorfs, Fabians fon. Virsnieki pret Hitleru. Stokholma, 1947 (Box 86, Folder 3)
    - Eglītis, Andrejs. Herre i Hojden! Jorden Brinner!: Dievs, Tava zeme deg!: lettlandsk bon. Stokholma, 1947 (Box 86, Folder 3)
    - Eglītis, Andrejs. Dievs, Tava zeme deg! Stokholma, 1948 (Box 86, Folder 3)
    - Eglītis, Andrejs. God, thy Earth is aflame: Latvian prayer: Dievs, Tava zeme deg! Stokholma, 1948 (Box 86, Folder 3)
      Copy nscribed by the author. Lai spēka nepietrūkst latviešiem svešumā- pastāvēt un cīnīties- māc. R. Zariņam. Andrejs Eglītis Stokholmā. 1947. g. jūlijā
    - Eglītis, Adolfs. The sower in exile. Alt-Erfrade, Schleswig-Holstein, 1948 (Box 86, Folder 3)
    - Shall Latvians perish? An urgent appeal of the Latvian National Council to the civilized world. Esslingen am Neckar, Baden-Württemberg, 1948 (Box 86, Folder 3)
    - Mazie Latvju raksti = Ornements lettons = Latvian ornaments = Lettische Ornamente. 2 daļas. Wedel-Holst, Schleswig-Holstein, 1948. (Box 86, Folder 4)
    - Voldemārs, H. The Baltic States: the first victims of Communist brutality. Valka, 1948 (Box 86, Folder 4)
    - We accuse: the Eastern power of despotism- the Western Ones of Indifference. [Place of publication not identified], 1948 (Box 86, Folder 4)
    - Burchard, A. Bischof Peter Harald Poelchau: Der letzte Bischof der evang.-luth.deutch-baltischen Gemeinden. Eine Erinnerung. Gross Biewende ub.Borssum, 1949 (Box 86, Folder 4)
    - Plensners, Aleksandrs. Informacija par latviešu leģionu. Pinneberg, Schleswig-Holstein, 1949 (Box 86, Folder 4)
    - Introiti, kolletes un draudzes lūgšanas. Hamburga, 1949 (Box 86, Folder 4)
    - Rožleja, Indriķis. Nīca, Bārta, Rucava: tautas tērpi. Lübeck, Schleswig-Holstein, 1950. (Box 86, Folder 5)
    - Tālā ceļā: kristīgs vadonis izceļotājiem. [Place of publication not identified]: Lutheran World Federation. Service to Refugees, Edition, 1950 (Box 86, Folder 5)
    - The Soviets against Church: persecution of religion in Soviet Latvia. Esslingen am Neckar, Baden-Württemberg, 1950 (Box 86, Folder 5)
    - Human freedom is being crushed: the story of deportations behind the Iron Curtain. Washington, D.C., 1951 (Box 86, Folder 5)
    - Life prospered in Latvia till 1940: own farm - great pleasure. [Place of publication not identified], 1951 (Box 86, Folder 5)
    - Forced labor in Soviet Union. Washington, D.C., 1952 (Box 86, Folder 6)
    - Latvieši Kanadā: rakstu krājums Kanādā, iznāk reizi gadā Latviešu dienās. Toronto, 1952 (Box 86, Folder 6)
    - Rirdans, E. Uncle Joe. London, 1952 (Box 86, Folder 6)
    - The red and the black: the Church in the communist state. New York, 1953 (Box 86, Folder 7)
    - Indriksons, Alfrēds. Mūsu baznīcas reformu nepieciešamība un iespējamība. Stokholma, 1954 (Box 86, Folder 7)
    - Blese, Ernests. Mūsu valoda savu vēsturisko cīņu gaitās. Londons, 1955 (Box 86, Folder 7)
    - Jēkabs Siebergs. Bostona, 1955 (Box 86, Folder 7)
    - Ārzemju cieniņi Padomju Latvijā. Berlin, 1958 (Box 86, Folder 7)
    - Latvijas skati = Vidy Latvii. Rīga, 1958 (Box 86, Folder 7)
    - Bērziņš, Alfreds. National resistance to Communist occupation of Latvia. [Place of publication not identified], 1960 (Box 86, Folder 7)
      2 copies: in English and French
    - The Baltic countries: Soviet colonies in the heart of Europe. New York, 1960 (Box 86, Folder 7)
    - Hoover, J. Edgar. The Communist menace. Washington, D.C., 1960 (Box 86, Folder 7)
    - Kuume aastat eelk New Yorgi Pauluse Kogudust, 1949-1959. New York, 1960 (Box 86, Folder 7)
    - Rīga = Riga: atklātņu komplekts. Rīga, 1961 (Box 87, Folder 1)
    - Viņa Ekscellence bīskaps Jāzeps Rancāns, 1911-12. jūnijs-1961; 1886-25. oktobris-1961 = The Most Reverend Bishop Joseph Rancans, D.D. Chicago, 1961 (Box 87, Folder 1)
    - The Baltic Women's Council, 1947-1962. New York, 1962 (Box 87, Folder 1)
    - Latvia. Original text by the Latvian Legation. Washington, D.C., 1962 (Box 87, Folder 1)
    - Čuibe, Leons. The Lutheran Church of Latvia in chains. Stockholm, 1963 (Box 87, Folder 1)
    - Ņujorkas Latviešu Biedrības 70 gadi. Ņujorka, 1963 (Box 87, Folder 1)
    - Punka, Andrejs. Daži mājieni runātājiem: apceres. Västerås, Sweden, 1963 (Box 87, Folder 1)
    - Freedom for captive Latvia! Milton, Mass., 1964 (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - Latvian Day, July 5, 1964, New York World's Fair. Rockville, 1964 (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - Jaunais latviešu bībeles izdevums: kā tapa jaunais vecās derības tulkojums un tagadējais kopējais bībeles jauniespiedums. Minneapolis, Minn., 1965 (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - Sigismunds Vidbergs: 75. Sigismunda Vidberga 50 gadu darbības jubilejas izstāde, Ligoa Dunkanes Galerijā, no 4. līdz 11. aprīlim 1965. gadā. Ņujorka, 1965 (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - We plead, we ask, we demand: Free the Baltic States! New York, 1965 (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - Communist oppression of Central and Eastern Europe: deeds and practices of Russian imperialism and colonialism in the heart of civilized Europe. New York, 1966 (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - Turpināsim strādāt diendienā! Take part in action to free the Baltic people! Chicago, Ill., 1967 (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - Ruņģis, Ivars. Reportiera rokas grāmata. Chicago, Ill., 1971 (Box 87, Folder 3)
    - Veinbergs, Alexander. Lutheranism and other denominations in the Baltic Republics. Chicago, Ill., 1971 (Box 87, Folder 3)
      Reprinted for private circulation from Aspects of Religion in the Soviet Union, 1917-1967. 1971
    - The 17 Latvian communist protest letter. Berlin, 1972 (Box 87, Folder 3)
    - Rumpeters, A. Soviet aggression against the Baltic states. New York., 1974 (Box 87, Folder 3)
    - 50 Jahre Sudkirche. Esslingen, 1976 (Box 87, Folder 3)
      Contains an article: Rozitis, Elmars. Die Gemeinde der Evangelisch-luterischen Kirche Lettlands in der Sudkirche zu Esslingen am Neckar
    - 85 gadu atceres izdevums Filadelfijas Latviešu Ev. Lut. Sv. Jāņa Draudzei. Filadelfija, 1978 (Box 87, Folder 4)
    - Jahna parahdischanas grahmata = The book of Revelations: text taken from the first Latvian Bible, printed in 1685. [Place of publication not identified], 1981, 1685 (Box 87, Folder 4)
    - Desmit rosmes gadi. Minesota, 1982 (Box 87, Folder 4)
    - The treatment of Christians in occupied Estonia, Latvia and Lithuania: representative documentation for the Eastern Canada in convention, June 21, 1985. Canada, 1985 (Box 87, Folder 4)
    - Zālīte, Valters. Ņujorkas latviešu Ev. Lut. draudzes Jonkeru baznīca divdesmit gados = Twenty years of the Yonkers Latvian Church, 1965.-1985. Ņujorka, 1985 (Box 87, Folder 4)
    - Katskiļu aizvējā: Ņujorkas latviesu Ev.-Lut. Draudzes nometne trīsdesmit gados, 1956.-1986. Ņujorka, 1986 (Box 87, Folder 5)
    - Ņujorkas latviešu kora desmit gadi, 1976.- 1986. New Jersey, 1986 (Box 87, Folder 5)
    - Rundāles pils = Rundalskii dvorets = The Rundale Palace. Rīga, 1990 (Box 87, Folder 5)
    - Rundāles pils. Rīga, 1991 (Box 87, Folder 5)
    - Rundāles Pils Muzeja 3. jaunieguvumu izstāde, 1986. - 1990.: katalogs. Rundāle, 1991 (Box 87, Folder 5)
    - Bundža, Kārlis. Mana dzimtā pilsēta Valka. Bloomfield, NJ, 1995 (Box 87, Folder 6)
    - Zālīte, Valters. Ņujorkas latviešu Ev. Lut. draudzes Jonkeru baznīca trīsdesmit gados = Thirty years of the Yonkers Latvian Church, 1965.-1995. Yonkers, NY, 1995 (Box 87, Folder 6)
    - Siliņa, Vera. Salas baznīcas un novada vēsture: no 1967. līdz 1995. gadam. Ņujorka, 1996 (Box 87, Folder 6)
    - Song Festivals. Pirmā latviešu dziesmu diena Kanādā, Pembroke, Canada, 1952 (Box 87, Folder 7)
    - Song Festivals. 1. un 2. latviešu dziesmu svētku Kanādā skatu krājums. Niagara Falls, 1957 (Box 87, Folder 7)
    - Song Festivals. Latviešu novada dziesmu svētki Indianapolē 1960. gada 2., 3., un 4. jūlijā: programma un vadonis. Indianapole, 1960 (Box 87, Folder 7)
    - Song Festivals. 3. Vispārējo latviešu dziesmu svētku ASV vadonis: Klīvlendā, Ohio, 1963. gada, 30. un 31. Augustā - 1. un 2. Septembrī. Klīvlenda, 1963 (Box 87, Folder 7)
    - Song Festivals. 4. Vispārējo latviešu A.S.V. dziesmu svētku vadonis. Cleveland, Ohio, 1968 (Box 88, Folder 1)
    - Song Festivals. 5. Latviešu dziesmu svētku Kanādā vadonis: no 27. junija - 5. jūlijam. Toronto, 1970 (Box 88, Folder 1)
    - Song Festivals. 7. Vispārējo latviešu dziesmu svētku vadonis: Milvokos, ASV, 1983. gadā, no 30. jūnija līdz 5. jūlijam. Milwaukee, WI, 1983 (Box 88, Folder 2)
    - Song Festivals. 8. Astoto Vispārējo dziesmu svētku vadonis: Indianapolē 1988. gadā no 29. jūnija lidz 4. jūlijam. Indianapolis, Ind., 1988 (Box 88, Folder 2)
    - Song Festivals. 21. Visparējie latviešu dziesmu svētki; 11. Deju svētki. Rīga, 1993 (Box 88, Folder 3)
  - Government documents
    - Relief of European populations. Hearings before the Committee on ways and means, House of Representatives, Sixty-sixth Congress, Second session. January 19. Washington, 1920 (Box 88, Folder 4)
    - Communist takeover and occupation of Estonia: special report no. 3 of the Select Committee on Communist Aggression, House of Representatives, Eighty-third Congress, Second session under authority of H. Res. 346 and H. Res. 438. Washington, 1955 (Box 88, Folder 4)
    - Communist takeover and occupation of Lithuania: special report no. 14 of the Select Committee on Communist Aggression, House of Representatives, Eghty-third Congress, Second session, under the authority of H. Res. 346 and H. Res. 438. Washington, 1955 (Box 88, Folder 4)
    - The crimes of Khrushchev: consultation with Dr. Vilis Masens, Mr. Vaclovas Sidzikauskas. Committee on Un-American activities, House of Representatives, Eighty-sixth Congress, First session, Sepember 21, 1959. Washington, 1959 (Box 88, Folder 4)
    - The technique of Soviet propaganda: a study presented by the Subcommittee to investigate the administration of the Internal Security Act and other internal security laws of the Committee on the Judiciary, United States Senate, Eighty-sixth congress, Second session. Washington, 1959 (Box 88, Folder 4)
    - Reprint of statements from the Congressional record: 87th Congress, Second Session, Forty-fourth anniversary of declaration of independence of Lithuania, February 15, 1962. (Box 88, Folder 4)
    - The church and state under communism: a special study prepared by the Law Library of the Library of Congress for the Subcomittee to investigate the administration of the internal security act and other internal security laws of the Committee on the Judiciary United States Senate. Vol. 4, Lithuania, Latvia and Estonia. Eighty-ninth congress, First session. Washington, 1965 (Box 88, Folder 4)
  - Maps
    - Mantnieks, Pēteris. Latvijas ceļu atlants. Rīga, 1939 (Box 88, Folder 5)
    - Latvijas ceļu karte. Rīga, 1940 (Box 88, Folder 6)
    - Cleartype general atlas of the world. New York, 1943 (Box 88, Folder 7)
    - Mantnieks, Pēteris. Pasaules atlants. Bruxelles, 1947 (Box 88, Folder 7)
    - Latvija. Bruxelles, 1950s (Flat-box 89, Folder 1)
  - Monographs
    Inscription to Rev. Richards Zariņš by the author
    - Muhsu dzeesmu grahmata: garigas dzeesmas. Riga, 1909 (Box 90, Folder 1)
    - Swehtas skaņas: garigas dzeesmas jaukteem koreem. Riga, 1911 (Box 90, Folder 3)
    - Dseesmu grahmata Ewanģ. Luteriskām Draudzem. Rīga, 1926 (Box 88, Folder 8)
    - Mūsu kunga un Pestītāja Jēzus Kristus Jaunā Derība. Rīga, 1937 (Box 88, Folder 8)
      Inscription by Rev. Richards Zariņš to his wife in 1937
    - Bihbele. Vezās un Jaunās Deribas Swehtee Raksti. Helsinki, 1948 (Box 90, Folder 2)
    - Do you speak English? = Waj runajat pa angliski? Riga, 1904 (Box 90, Folder 3)
    - Kallmeyer, Theodor. Die evangelischen Kirchen und Prediger Kurlands. Riga, 1910 (Box 90, Folder 1)
    - Neumann, Wilhelm. Der Dom zu St. Marien in Riga. Riga, 1912 (Box 90, Folder 4)
    - Szlupas, John. Lithuania in retrospect and prospect. New York, 1915 (Box 91, Folder 1)
    - Duzmans, Karl (Ducmans, Kārlis). Lettland förr och nu. Stockholm, 1926 (Box 91, Folder 2)
    - Schabert, Oskar. Baltisches Märtyrerbuch. Berlin, 1926 (Box 91, Folder 3)
    - Tirzas baznīca, 1826-1926. Photocopy.Tirza, 1926 (Box 91, Folder 4)
    - Nonācs, Otto. Mācītāju ziņojumi par 1905. gada revolūciju: ar autografiem tekstā. Rīga, 1930 (Box 91, Folder 5)
    - Profesora dr. K. Baloža un profesora dr. P. Zālītes Runas Saeimā. Rīga, 1931 (Box 91, Folder 6)
    - Svensktiden i Lettland = Zviedru laikmets Latvijā. Rīga, 1934 (Flat-box 89, Folder 2)
      Inscription for Rev, Richards Zariņš
    - Adamovičs, L. Latviskums mūsu dievkalpojumos. Photocopy. Rīga, 1939 (Box 91, Folder 7)
    - Švabe, Arveds. Latvia on the Baltic Sea. Hanau, Hesse, 1947 (Box 91, Folder 8)
    - Švabe, Arveds. The story of Latvia: a historical survey. Stockholm, 1950 (Box 91, Folder 8)
    - Bērziņš, Arturs. Jānis Jaunsudrabiņš. Västerås, Sweden, 1952 (Box 91, Folder 9)
    - Spiritus at Veritas: [savu augsti cienījamo kollēgu, draugu un audzinātāju Profesoru Dr. theol. Kārli Kundziņu septiņdesmit mūža atcerē 1953. gada 12. aprīlī sveiciana ...]. Eutin, Schleswig-Holstein, 1953 (Box 91, Folder 9)
    - Rüdiger, Wilhelm von. Aus dem letzten Kapitel deutsch-baltischer Geschichte in Lettland, 1919 - 1945. Bovender uber Göttingen, Lower Saxony, 1954 (Box 92, Folder 1)
    - Goppers, Miķelis. Kolchozi: posts un verdzība Latvijas laukos. Stockholm, 1957 (Box 92, Folder 1)
    - Ozols, Jānis G. Klaras Elizabetes Ozolas piemiņai. Ņujorka, 1960. (Box 92, Folder 2)
    - Lakstīgala, Pēteris. Manas dzīves atmiņas. [Place of publication not identified], 1966 (Box 92, Folder 2)
    - Report on the implementation of the Helsinki final act of August 1, 1975 in Soviet occupied Latvia. Rockville, Md, 1980 (Box 92, Folder 3)
    - Gulbis, Osvalds. Sekot Kristum: svētrunas un apceres. Linkoln, Nb, 1981 (Box 92, Folder 4)
    - Mesters, Ēriks. Latvijas Evanģēliski Luteriskās Baznīcas Bīskaps Dr. theol. Kārlis Irbe. Rīga, 1994 (Box 92, Folder 5)
      The copy signed by the author Ēriks Mesters
  - Serial publications: Newspapers, journals, bulletins and related materials
    - Amerikas Wehstnesis: politisks, literārisks laikraksts. Bostona. Mass., 1897-1920 (Flat-box 93, Folder 1)
      1897.- N 11, 1898.- N 21, 1909.- N 12, 1910.- N 8, 20, 1915.- N 7, 1916.- N4, 14, 19, 20, 1917.- N 1, 3, 15, 1918.- N 8, 10, 18, 1919.- N 4, 7, 8, 9, 11, 15, 19, 23, 1920.- N 1, 3, 4, 7, 10
    - Amerikas Atbalss. Ņujorka, 1921-1922 (Flat-box 93, Folder 2)
      1921.- 23, 1922.- 4, 6, 8
    - Jaunā Balss: ilustrets nedeļas laikraksts. Rīga, 1923. N 1, 1924. N 1 (Flat-box 89, Folder 4)
    - Mehnescha Apskats. Ņujorka, 1923. N 2, 1926. N 1 (Flat-box 89, Folder 5)
    - Kristīgs Vadonis. Rīga, 1926. N 3, 10 (Flat-box 93, Folder 3)
    - Open Forum. Ņujorka, January, 1927 (Flat-box 89, Folder 6)
    - Amerikas Zihna: politisks, literarisks un sinatnisks laikraksts. Ņujorka, 1926. N 19, 1928. N 10 (Flat-box 93, Folder 4)
    - Flyers of Latvian leftist societies. New York, [Year of publications not identified] (Flat-box 89, Folder 8)
    - Flyer, "Cīņas Biedri". New York, 1932 (Flat-box 89, Folder 9)
    - Sunday Mirror. September 6, 1936 (Flat-box 93, Folder 5)
      Contains an article on Latvia
    - Sunday News. March 6, 1938 (Flat-box 93, Folder 5)
      National flags as they were in 1938
    - Latwijas Brihwibas Draugu Biļetens. Ņujorka, 1938, N 1 (Flat-box 95, Folder 1)
    - Zvans: politiski-sabiedriski-saimniecisks žurnāls. Rīga, 1930. N 2 (Box 92, Folder 7)
    - Swehtdeenas Rihts: Latvijas Evaņģeliski Luteriskās Baznīcas laikraksts. Rīga, 1938. N 2, 1989, N 10 (Flat-box 95, Folder 2)
    - Strahdneeku Zihņa. Bostona, Mass., 1938. N 1 (Flat-box 94, Folder 1)
    - Latvijas Nacionālā Opera 1938. gadam, 1938/39. gadam. Rīga (Box 92, Folder 8)
    - Rīts. Rīga, 1939. N 134 (Flat-box 94, Folder 2)
    - Latvian-American Chamber of Commerce: Bulletin. New York, January, 1940 (Flat-box 95, Folder 3)
    - Dzimtene. Ņujorka, 1941. N 4, 5 (Flat-box 95, Folder 4)
    - Baznīcas Ziņas. Rīga, 1943, 1944. (Flat-box 94, Folder 3)
      1943.- N 24, 27, 28, 31, 1944.- N 18, 22, 34, 35, 41, 50
    - Latvju Ziņas. Stokholma, 1944. N 2, 1945. N 1 (Flat-box 94, Folder 4)
    - The New Leader. 1945, April 14; October 27, N 43 (Flat-box 94, Folder 3)
      Contains articles on history and political situation in Latvia
    - Trimda: Exile Latvian Newspaper. Lauenburg, Schleswig-Holstein, 1945. N 42, 43 (Flat-box 94, Folder 5)
    - Latvian Information Bulletin issued by The Latvian Legation. Washington, D.C., April, July 1945, May 1946, November 1959 (Flat-box 95, Folder 5)
    - Mūsu Diena: 18. novembris. Stokholma, 1946 (Flat-box 94, Folder 6)
    - Jaunais Vārds: latviešu literatūras un mākslas mēnešraksts Mērbekā. Meerbeck, Lower Saxony, 1946. N 1, 2 (Box 92, Folder 9)
    - Latvju Vārds. Stokholma, 1946. N 16, 1963. N 29 (Flat-box 94, Folder 8)
    - Tiesībnieks: apskats latvju juristiem tiesību jautājumos. Blomberg, North Rhine-Westphalia, 1947-1949 (Flat-box 94, Folder 7)
      1947.- N 1, 2, 1948.- N 4, N 5, 1949.- N 6, 7, 8
    - Latvju Raksti Brīvā Latvija. Roma, 1947 (Flat-box 95, Folder 6)
      1947. N 15/16, 18, 19, 20 Published by Gustavs Celmiņš
    - YMCA Biļetens. Würzburg, Northern Bavaria. 1947. N 10, 11, 13 (Flat-box 94, Folder 9)
    - American World Intelligence, 1948. Vol II, N 11 (Box 92, Folder 10)
    - Tālos Krastos. Philadelphia, Pa, 1948. N 1 (Flat-box 96, Folder 1)
    - Latvju Zaltene: rokdarbu mēnešraksts Latvju sievietei. Münster, North Rhine-Westphalia, 1948/49, 1957, 1965 (Box 92, Folder 11)
      1948/49. N 3, 1957. N 29, 1965.? N 43
    - Dzirkstele. Köln, North Rhine-Westphalia, 1949. N 6, 7/8 (Box 92, Folder 12)
    - Latvijas Ev. Lut. Baznīcas Vidusanglijas Draudzes Vēstnesis = The Latvian Lutheran Church News Bulletin for Parish Midlands. Wistow, Cambridgeshire, England, 1949. N 3/4, 5 (Flat-box 95, Folder 7)
    - Latvija aiz Dzelzs Priekškara. Stokholma, 1949. N 31, 32 (Box 92, Folder 13)
      Contains quotations concerning political etc. conditions in Latvia, from the broadcastings of the radio in Soviet Latvia. Published by Latviešu Nacionalais Fonds
    - Jaunzelandes Latviešu Draudzei. Marton, North Island, New Zealand, 1949-1950 (Box 92, Folder 14)
      Latvian Evangelical Lutheran Church of New Zealand. Issues- 1949. nov., dec., 1950. janv., febr., marts, apr., jūl., nov., dec.
    - Amerikas Latweetis: laikraksts politikai, zinatnei un mahslai. Bostona, Mass., 1949, 1965, 1966, 1973 (Flat-box 96, Folder 2)
      1949. N 42, 1965. N 1, 1966. N 4, 1973. N 15
    - Svešos Ceļos. Onida, South Dacota, 1950. N 2 (Box 97, Folder 1)
    - ABN informācija. Baden-Württemberg, 1950. Februaris (Box 97, Folder 1)
      ABN - Antiboļševistisko Nāciju Bloks
    - Information on Conditions behind the Iron Curtain. Stockholm, 1950 (Box 97, Folder 2)